Edward G. O'Neill Papers
Edward G. O'Neill Papers
1931-1944
O'Neill, Edward G.
5 linear ft.
Correspondence, manuscripts and published material of the New York attorney, assistant attorney general, and special prosecutor.
2679034
Biographical History
Edward G. O'Neill (1894-1972) was a New York State lawyer and assistant state attorney general.
Born in Brooklyn, New York, O'Neill received his A. B. from Michigan University and his LLB from Fordham. He served in France during World War I, receiving a Purple Heart and the Croix de Guerre. He received his law degree in 1921 from Fordham University and was admitted to the New York State bar the same year. He practiced in Brooklyn until 1939 when he was appointed assistant attorney general for the state of New York; he later served as special judge of the Orange County (NY) Court, special prosecutor of local officials of the Hod Carriers Union Local 17, and special U.S. Attorney to investigate graft in the construction of Camp Shanks in Orangeburg.
After his retirement from the law, O'Neill was an active participant in the social and civic life of Newburgh, New York, where among other things he was an organizer of the Newburgh Tax Commission and president of the Newburgh Chamber of Commerce.
Scope and Contents of the Collection
The Edward G. O'Neill Papers consist of two sets of material which have not been integrated.
The 1966 set contains correspondence, subject files, manuscripts and published material. Correspondence (1931-1943) includes both incoming and outgoing correspondence. There is also a correspondence book of incoming and outgoing letters arranged chronologically. Subject files (1941-1943) contains material on topics ranging from labor to Orange County investigations. Manuscripts consists of scripts for radio broadcasts. Published material contains news clippings about O'Neill and others.
The 1979 set contains a single series of Subject files, comprising legal documents, speeches, clippings, correspondence, blueprints, and other material.
Arrangement of the Collection
1966 set: Incoming correspondence is arranged alphabetically by author; outgoing is arranged chronologically. Subject files are arranged alphabetically by subject. Manuscripts (radio scripts) are arranged chronologically.
1979 set: Single series, arranged alphabetically.
Subject and Genre Headings
New York State; Politics, government and public administration; O'Neill, Edward G.; New York (State). -- Attorney General's Office.; Lawyers -- New York (State); Clippings (information artifacts); Correspondence.; Radio scripts.; Lawyers.; Special prosecutors.
Access Restrictions
The majority of our archival and manuscript collections are housed offsite and require advanced notice for retrieval. Researchers are encouraged to contact us in advance concerning the collection material they wish to access for their research.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Edward G. O'Neill, 1967.
Inventory
- Correspondence (1966)
  - Incoming
    - B - V (Box 1)
    - Reed, Hoyt, Washburn and Clay (Box 1)
    - Speculation, New York - Town Clerk (Box 1)
    - Unidentified (Box 1)
  - Outgoing
    - 1939-1943, 3 folders (Box 1)
  - Book
    - Incoming and outgoing, 1934-1941 (Box 1)
- Subject files (1966)
  - Financial (Box 1)
  - Labor (Box 1)
  - Legal documents (Box 1)
  - Lists (Box 1)
  - Notes (Box 1)
  - Orange County Investigation (Box 1)
- Manuscripts (1966)
  - Radio scripts
    - September 1942-July 1943 (Box 2)
    - August 1943-June 1944 (Box 3)
- Published Material (1966)
  - News clippings about (Box 3)
  - News clippings about others (Box 3)
- Subject files (1979)
  - A (Box 4)
  - D. Sterling Agnew (Box 4)
  - American Legion (Box 4)
  - Atlas Roofing Company (Box 4)
  - Area Army Installations (Box 4)
  - B (Box 4)
  - Barton, Colonel LeRoy IGD (Box 4)
  - William Bennett, autobiography article (Box 4)
  - Bennett Committee (Box 4)
  - Bennett vs Cronin (Box 4)
  - Blachly, Fred (Box 4)
  - Blueprints (Box 4)
  - Boy Scouts (Box 4)
  - Bradley, Mary G. (Box 4)
  - C (Box 4)
  - Camp Shanks, 2 folders (Box 4)
  - Carpenters Local 301 (Box 4)
  - Chamber of Commerce (Box 4)
  - Clark, Tom C. (Assistant Attorney General) (Box 4)
  - Conden vs Ondriska (Box 4)
  - Conference memoirs and photostats (Box 4)
  - Continental Village (Box 4)
  - Coronway, H. Roy (Box 4)
  - D (Box 4)
  - Decker, John C. (Box 4)
  - Estate of Rose Dwyer (Box 4)
  - E (Box 4)
  - Embarkation, New York Port of (Box 4)
  - Chief of Engineers, USA (Box 4)
  - Eureka Shipbuilding Corporation
    - C-10 contest (Box 4)
    - Contract of 1944, 2 folders (Box 5)
    - Correspondence (Box 5)
    - Union (Box 5)
  - Eureka Shipbuilding Corporation and the Industrial Union of Marine and Shipbuilding Workers of America, draft of agreement (Box 5)
  - F (Box 5)
  - FBI investigation
    - Dann, Robert Ray (Box 5)
    - Requests for (Box 5)
  - Joseph S. Fay (Box 5)
  - Federal Grand Jury (Box 5)
  - Stewart Field (Box 5)
  - Fish (Box 5)
  - Foreign policy (Box 5)
  - G (Box 5)
  - H (Box 5)
  - Hard, Williams (Box 5)
  - I (Box 5)
  - Income tax returns (Box 5)
  - Inspector General, USA (Box 5)
  - J (Box 5)
  - K (Box 5)
  - Joseph Kahn arbitration case (Box 5)
  - L (Box 5)
  - Legal memoranda, opinions (Box 5)
  - M (Box 5)
  - James P. McGranery (Box 5)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 5)
  - N (Box 5)
  - Newspaper clippings (Box 5)
  - O (Box 5)
  - E. G. O'Neill, personal (Box 5)
  - P (Box 5)
  - Pedolsky, Samuel (Box 5)
  - Wills of Benjamin and Ethel Peretz (Box 5)
  - Philippines (Box 5)
  - Prindle, Charles H. (Box 5)
  - R (Box 6)
  - Radio notes (Box 6)
  - Red Cross (Box 6)
  - Rotary (Box 6)
  - S (Box 6)
  - Shipbuilding industry, zone standards and amendments (Box 6)
  - Sloan vs Warden (Box 6)
  - State Insurance Fund, compensation claim of Robert Sibrova (Box 6)
  - T (Box 6)
  - E. Totenelly Sons (Box 6)
  - U (Box 6)
  - Unanswered (Box 6)
  - V (Box 6)
  - W (Box 6)
  - Woodcock, A. W. W. (Box 6)
  - Y (Box 6)
  - Zaffarano, Anthony (Box 6)
  - Abstracts of titles and searches to property in Newburgh, New York, 1 volume (Box 6)
  - Abstracts of titles and searches to property in Newburgh, New York, 2 volumes (Box 7)